<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Pennine Post</title>
    <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Pennine Post</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>January 2025</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2025-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2025-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;snow-and-fog-it-must-be-january&#34;&gt;Snow and fog, it must be January&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How&amp;rsquo;s your 2025 planning coming along? With a bit of luck you&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get out on the snowy hills but even if not, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a packed issue of 2025 diary dates to help you plan your next adventure. Book a trip, try a competition or spend an evening setting up your instruments and tracking, it won&amp;rsquo;t be long until the thermals are launching us skywards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;get-the-beers-in-its-club-night&#34;&gt;Get the beers in, it&amp;rsquo;s club night&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Winter&amp;rsquo;s here and that means club nights. Pub grub, a beer and talking flying for a couple of hours, what could be better than that? Well flying could, obviously, and a few of us have managed some bumpy days and smoother evenings to scratch that itch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for flyable windows and interesting club night talks and we&amp;rsquo;ll be back with another issue in January.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;last-of-the-summer-flying&#34;&gt;Last of the summer flying&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suddenly it feels like Autumn. There are still a few XC&amp;rsquo;s being flown but the leaves are starting to turn and this will be the last regular monthly newsletter until next season. We&amp;rsquo;ll drop to just a couple of issues through the winter and hope to pack them full of frosty flying pics before it&amp;rsquo;s spring thermal warnings time all over again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks as always for your contributions. We&amp;rsquo;ve got tales of flying in France from Chris and Doug, advice from Brian on how to cope with flyable days when you can&amp;rsquo;t get out to fly, plus a top notch gallery. Cover picture was a tough choice this month!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>August 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;cloudbase-is-just-a-thermal-away&#34;&gt;Cloudbase is just a thermal away&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You wait around for ages and then all the flying comes at once. Except for your newsletter editor who went to the windy Westcountry for a fortnight&amp;rsquo;s family holiday. Never mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve got a photo bonanza this month. More XC tales from Brian, a fabulous photo diary of comp flying in Slovenia from Elliott and the gallery is stuffed with goodies too, including epic views of the Alps from Chris and Sean and even one or two snaps from Parlick.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>July 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;come-back-summer-we-werent-finished-yet&#34;&gt;Come back summer, we weren&amp;rsquo;t finished yet&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a poor summer so far for flying, with too much wind and rain for us to get much play time. Pilots have been rewarded for late trips to Parlick when the wind dies down though, including last Friday and Sunday, which as long as you were OK with a slightly breezy launch from below the wall were really beautiful evenings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve got some cracking photos of the LCC from John Oliver this month, spectacular XC pics from Brian, an important note about Winter Hill and tips on thermalling etiquette from our safety officer. The conditions have been putting a dampener on weekend XC possibilities for a lot of us and I seem to write &amp;lsquo;fingers crossed for better weather&amp;rsquo; in every issue, so, erm, fingers crossed for better weather. Yep, that&amp;rsquo;ll sort it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>June 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;champagne-corks-and-festivals&#34;&gt;Champagne Corks and Festivals&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May came and went with the weather providing more short flying windows, including gracing Pennine Fest with a morning&amp;rsquo;s flying on Parlick. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s grabbing bits and pieces of flying where they can so fingers crossed for better as we move into summer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This one was looking like a short issue and then you lot suddenly came through with some fantastic contributions. A cynic might suspect the weather&amp;rsquo;s got you all bored and desperately looking for something to do! We have huge news (and exclusive pics) from the European Paragliding Championships, loads from Pennine Fest including a brilliant write-up by Fiona Dalzell, tales of the BP Cup in Sopot from John Murphy, competitions, coaching, a reminder about important site rules (and a reminder to remind &lt;em&gt;others&lt;/em&gt; about those rules too) and a new Top Tips section.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-that-beeping-sound&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that beeping sound?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a start to April that prompted the BBC to run a front page article titled &amp;ldquo;Why is it raining so much?&amp;rdquo;, we&amp;rsquo;ve finally started to be rewarded with some flying weather. Saturday 20th April saw pilots high over Pendle and Longridge and since then it&amp;rsquo;s been, well, if not exactly epic then at least occasionally flyable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The BBC asks the question on all of our minds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;quick-somebody-tell-the-weather-its-spring&#34;&gt;Quick, somebody tell the weather it&amp;rsquo;s spring&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to issue 2!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last month&amp;rsquo;s votes have been counted and we&amp;rsquo;re now officially The Pennine Post so set your bookmarks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/&#34;&gt;post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;ll aim to be back on the first Tuesday of each month with news, events and pictures of all of the spectacular flying we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing. Or pictures of parawaiting. Probably mostly parawaiting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who&amp;rsquo;s sent contributions this month. The Pennine Post is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; newsletter so if you want a good read to take your mind off work then you need to send something in.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Email anytime to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:editor@penninesoaringclub.org.uk&#34;&gt;editor@penninesoaringclub.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; or we also have a handy &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd3NJQKlmLjjlh-nZGQKaeXzN6dSSL2PHzKRXFYAy_Bw7SC9w/viewform?usp=sf_link&#34;&gt;web form&lt;/a&gt; that you can use to ping over pictures and stories. If you&amp;rsquo;re on a hill, take a photo!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March 2024</title>
      <link>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://post.penninesoaringclub.org.uk/posts/2024-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;chairmans-chunterings&#34;&gt;Chairman’s Chunterings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the PSC newsletter, grateful thanks to the efforts of our new committee member, Neil Charles for creating the first of what we hope will be many issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, the AGM came and went with a few surprises along the way. After several years doing an excellent job, Simon Scott stood down as chairman, and as I try to step into his shoes, I’d like to thank him on behalf of all the members for the great work he’s done in guiding the club and keeping us all together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
